Guide to the Frances Frost Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Frances Frost papers
1919-1976
1928-1959
YCAL MSS 33
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
7.75
(16 boxes)
The papers contain correspondence, journals, financial papers, scrapbooks and drafts of Frost's poetry, short stories, and longer works.
Other Storage Formats: oversize
Frost, Frances, 1905-1959
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The papers were purchased from Frances Frost's executrix, Mrs. N. Carr Grace, on the Danford Barney Fund in May 1972. In March 1977, Harper & Row, Inc. donated the galleys and mock-ups for the 1976 reissue of Christmas in the Woods.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
FRANCES MARY FROST (1905-1959)
Frances Mary Frost, poet, novelist, and author of children's books, was born in St. Albans, Vermont, on August 3, 1905, to Amos and Susan Keefe Frost. She attended Middlebury College from 1923-26 and later graduated from the University of Vermont with the degree of Bachelor of Philosophy in 1931.
Frost worked as a reporter in 1927 and taught creative poetry at the University of Vermont from 1929-31 before devoting her time to writing. Her first book, Hemlock Wall, was published by the Yale University Press in 1929 as part of the Yale Series of Younger Poets. It was succeeded by ten volumes of verse, including Woman of this Earth, published by Houghton, Mifflin, & Co. in 1934. She was a frequent contributor of poetry and fiction to the New York Herald Tribune and to such magazines as Harper's and Saturday Review. In addition to the four volumes of poetry she wrote for children-- Pool in the Meadow, Christmas in the Woods, The Little Whistler, and The Little Naturalist --Frost published over a dozen books of juvenile fiction, including the Windy Foot series. Farrar & Rinehart also published five of her novels between 1936-42, including Yoke of Stars, Uncle Snowball, and Village of Glass. She spent her summers from 1931-37 at the MacDowell Colony in Peterboro, New Hampshire, and received the Shelley Memorial Award from the Poetry Society of America along with Lola Ridge and the Golden Rose Award of the New England Poetry Club in 1933.
Both of Frost's marriages--to W. Gordon Blackburn of Portland, Oregon, on April 4, 1926 and to Samuel Gaillard Stoney of Charleston, South Carolina, on September 18, 1933--ended in divorce. She spent the last years of her life in New York City and died of cancer at her home at 79 Horatio Street on February 11, 1959. She was survived by her son, the poet Paul Blackburn, and by her daughter, Sister Marguerite of the Order of St. Joseph.
Scope and Contents
The Frances Frost Papers contain correspondence, journals, financial records, scrapbooks, and drafts of Frost's poetry, novels, children's books, and short stories. The papers span the years 1919-76, but the bulk of the material dates from 1928-59. The Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library also owns a life-size portrait head in composite of Frances Frost (one of three) by Anita Weschler that was donated by Jack A. Goldfarb in May, 1972.
Series I, Writings (Boxes 1-11), is divided into four sections, Children's Literature, Novels, Poetry, and Shorter Works. The section on Children's Literature begins with drafts of Frost's narrative adaptation of Gian-Carlo Menotti's opera, Amahl and the Night Visitors. Box 1, folder 2 contains a portion of the dialogue from the opera, which Frost preserved intact, and a reproduction of "The Adoration of the Magi" by Hieronymous Bosch, which inspired Menotti. There are also some articles about Harvard in Box 15, folder 268, upon which Frost based her book The Cat That Went to College. A number of galleys and page proofs for the Windy Foot books are also preserved with the Oversize material. Whittlesey House published Frost's juvenilia, beginning in 1943 with Legends of the United Nations, a collection of folk tales from all over the world. They rejected "Paddy Reilly," however, in 1955 because the manuscript was "too episodic" (Box 2, folder 25).
Like her other writings, Frost based her novels upon her New England upbringing and often featured strong female characters. According to a scrapbook of reviews about her second novel, Yoke of Stars, Frost had a flowing lyric style, "appealing human characters," and a "hearty and wholesome message" (Box 13, folder 256). The Novels subseries contains contracts for three other novels, a synopsis of Uncle Snowball, which was not recommended for a movie "unless a quiet, serene story is wanted" (Box 3, folder 40), and various drafts for her last novel, Village of Glass.
The bulk of the Writings series consists of poetry, found in Boxes 3-10. Thirty-one notebooks covering the period 1928-59 begin the section. They are arranged chronologically and contain early drafts and publishing information about each poem, such as submissions, rejections, and acceptances. Financial information concerning the poems may also be found with Frost's financial records in Box 12, folders 238-42. Over one thousand loose poems, arranged alphabetically by title, follow the notebooks in letter general files. Books of verse and printed versions of poems in magazines are given separate folders and interfiled alphabetically by title. Poetry written for both adults and children is represented in the subseries. Some of the poems were later set to music by Earl Roland Larson and may be found with Shorter Works in Boxes 10-11. A folder of newspaper clippings of Frost's poems completes the section. Other printed versions of her poems are found in scrapbooks (Box 13, folders 255-57). An untitled draft filed in Box 10, folder 166 was probably the last collection of verse that Frost wrote before her death.
Shorter Works include short stories, essays, plays, and music scores. Both juvenile and adult fiction are represented in this section. Most of Frost's stories are in manuscript, although a few printed versions from magazines are included, together with one recording on magnetic tape of the "Voice of America's" broadcast of "The Heart Being Perished."
Series II, Personal Papers (Boxes 12-14), is arranged alphabetically by type of material. There are twenty-six folders of letters Frost received from magazines like Virginia Quarterly and Atlantic Monthly, from George Abbe at the Book Club for Poetry, who published This Rowdy Heart in 1954 through the Golden Quill Press (Box 12, folder 213), and from the Arthur P. Schmidt Company, which sent her ten dollars for every poem they set to music. Poets like Edwin Arlington Robinson sent her wedding congratulations, Witter Bynner praised her poem "Rocking Chair," and Karlton Kelm admired her first novel Innocent Summer. Ivan Beede wrote from the MacDowell Colony wishing her a "strenuous, happy, and fruitful visit to Germany" and quipping that "the beer can't have gone Nazi" (Box 12, folder 211). There is also a letter from Gertrude Stein to Lindley Hubbell about the writer Windell Wilcox. The Library of Congress sent a permission form signed by N. Carr Grace in 1968, releasing her rights to the library's sound recording of Frost reading poetry in 1955.
Frost's journals begin with two early diaries from high school and a third of her impressions of Germany in 1936. In two later notebooks, she records overheard conversations and lists such things as names to be used in her writing. There are only two early photographs of Frost in the papers and one of James Houston Spencer. Three scrapbooks include printed clippings of Frost's poems, articles about her, and reviews of her work from 1930-58. Seven additional scrapbooks contain the poetry of other writers, such as Robert Frost (to whom she was not related), Dorothy Parker, and William Carlos Williams. There are also clippings of poems by other residents of the MacDowell Colony, such as Babette Deutsch and Louis Untermeyer. Three folders of writings by others complete the series. Alice Hunt Bartlett's article about American poetry, filed here, mentions Frost and a play written at the MacDowell Colony in 1936 in which Frost is described as "A daughter of rock-ribbed Vermont," "An interpreter of life -- and of nature," and "A New England pagan" (Box 14, folder 266).
Children's literature; Lyric poetry; Poetry -- Authorship; Poetry, Modern -- 20th Century; Poets, American -- 20th Century; Women poets; New England -- Poetry; Vermont -- Poetry; Journals (notebooks); Poems; Scrapbooks; Sheet music; Poets; Abbe, George, 1911-1989; Frost, Frances, 1905-1959; Larson, Earl Roland; Edward MacDowell Association
- Writings, 1928-63; Series I; 4.5; (11 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  Boxes 1-11 hold Series I, Writings, divided into four sections, Children's Literature, Novels, Poetry, and Shorter Works. Each section is arranged by title and thereafter by the probable order of creation.
  - CHILDREN'S LITERATURE
    - Notes, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Amahl and the Night Visitors
      - Notes, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Typescript, 1952 Mar 25 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - "Final" typescript, 1952 Apr 1 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Typescript, variant fragment, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - The Cat That Went to College
      Related Archival Materials note
      See: Oversize, Box 15, folder 268
    - Christmas is Shaped Like Stars
      See: Oversize, Box 15, folder 269
    - Fireworks for Windy Foot
      - Notes, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Early typescript, chapters 1-16, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 7-10)
      - Typescript, chapters 1-3, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - Reviews, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Legends of the United Nations
      - Typescripts of four stories, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - Page proofs, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 14-16)
    - The Little Donkey: typescript and reviews, 1959, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Little Fox: illustrations by Morgan Dennis, 1952 May 28 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Maple Sugar for Windy Foot
      See also: Oversize, Box 15, folders 270-73
      - Typescript with printer's annotations, chapters 1-10, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 19-21)
      - Typescript with printer's annotations, chapters 11-14, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 22)
      - Mock-ups and page proofs for title page, 1949 Nov (Box 2, Folder 23)
      - Advertisement, 1950 spring (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - "Paddy Reilly"
      - Early typescript, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 25-26)
      - Typescript, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 27)
      - Typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - "Paddy Reilly: Dog of New York": typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Sleigh Bells for Windy Foot
      See: Oversize, Box 16, folder 274
    - Then Came Timothy
      See also: Oversize, Box 16, folders 275-76
      - Typescript, "corrected copy", 1950 (Box 2, Folder 30-31)
      - Typescript, "master copy", 1950 (Box 2, Folder 32-33)
      - Typescript, carbon, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 34-35)
      - Typescript fragments, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Windy Foot at the Country Fair: typescript fragments (Box 2, Folder 37)
      See also: Oversize, Box 16, folder 277
  - NOVELS
    - Innocent Summer: contract, 1935 May 9 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Kate Trimingham: contract, 1939 Dec 21 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Uncle Snowball: synopses, 1939 Dec 14 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Village of Glass
      - Contract, 1937 Jul 8 (Box 3, Folder 41)
      - "Original" typescript, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 42)
      - Typescript with printer's marks, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 43-45)
    - Yoke of Stars: reviews, 1939 Jan (Box 3, Folder 46)
      See also: Box 13, folder 256
  - POETRY
    - Notebooks: holograph, 1928-33 (Box 3, Folder 47-54)
    - Notebooks: holograph, 1933 Apr-Sep (Box 4, Folder 55-56)
    - Notebooks: typescript, 1933-42 (Box 4, Folder 57-63)
    - Notebooks: typescript, 1942-53 (Box 5, Folder 64-71)
    - Notebooks: typescript, 1953-59 (Box 6, Folder 72-77)
    - "A" general: drafts, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 78-80)
    - "B" general: drafts, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 81-82)
    - "The Ballad of Johnny Appleseed": typescripts, 1949, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 83)
    - Blue Harvest: contract, 1930 Oct 14 (Box 7, Folder 84)
    - "Boy in the Fog": typescript, 1935 May 28 (Box 7, Folder 85)
    - "C" general: drafts, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 86-89)
    - "The Children's Almanac": typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 90)
    - Christmas in the Woods: typescript with printer's marks, 1976 Jan (Box 7, Folder 91)
      See also: Oversize, Box 16, folders 278-79
    - "Clover for Breakfast": typescript, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 92)
    - "Compass in the Corner"
      - Typescript, 1949 Jun (Box 7, Folder 93)
      - Typescript, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 94)
    - "D" general: drafts, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 95-96)
    - "E" general: drafts, 1946, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 97-98)
    - "F" general: drafts, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 99-100)
    - "Fusion": printed in Poetry, vol. XLII, no. V, 1933 Aug (Box 7, Folder 101)
    - "G" general: drafts, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 102-03)
    - "H" general: drafts, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 104-05)
    - Hemlock Wall: contract, 1929 Jun 17 (Box 8, Folder 106)
    - "History of America": printed in The Poetry Society of Georgia, vol. XI, 1935 (Box 8, Folder 107)
    - "I" general: drafts, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 108)
    - "J" general: drafts, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 109)
    - "K" general: drafts, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 110)
    - "L" general: drafts, 1954, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 111-13)
    - "Last Generation": printed in Poetry, vol. XLIV, no. II, 1934 May (Box 8, Folder 114)
    - The Little Naturalist
      - Typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 115)
      - Reviews, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 116)
    - "M" general: drafts, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 117-18)
    - Mid-Century: typescript, 1946 (Box 8, Folder 119)
    - "N" general: drafts, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 120-21)
    - "New Hampshire Village" and "Comic Yawn": printed in Yankee, 1959 Aug (Box 8, Folder 122)
    - "O" general: drafts, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 123-24)
    - "Of a Corn-Husking, Some Jugs of Cider and a Fiddle": typescript, 1935 Jul (Box 8, Folder 125)
    - "P" general: drafts, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 126-28)
    - "Poems for Six"
      See: Box 9, folder 129
    - Pool in the Meadow
      - Contract, 1933 Jan 20 (Box 9, Folder 129)
      - Review, 1934 Mar (Box 9, Folder 130)
    - "Q" general: drafts, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 131)
    - "R" general: drafts, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 132-34)
    - Road to America
      - Typescript, 1934 Jan 1 (Box 9, Folder 135)
      - Typescript, 1936 (Box 9, Folder 136)
      - Contract, 1936 Jul 15 (Box 9, Folder 137)
    - "S" general: drafts, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 138-44)
    - "Snowed Under": printed in Yankee, vol. 18, no. 10, 1954 Oct (Box 9, Folder 145)
    - "T" general, 1944, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 146-47)
    - These Acres
      - Contract, 1932 Feb 1 (Box 9, Folder 148)
      - Review, 1932 Sep 25 (Box 9, Folder 149)
    - This Rowdy Heart
      See also: Oversize, Box 16, folder 280
      - Contract, [1954] Feb 17 (Box 9, Folder 150)
      - Reviews, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 151)
    - "Three Poems": printed in Poetry, vol. XLVIII, no. V, 1936 Aug (Box 9, Folder 152)
    - "Three Poems": printed in The Popular Educator, no. 9, 1939 Sep 27 (Box 9, Folder 153)
    - "Two New England Poems": printed in The Popular Educator, no. 16, 1939 Nov 15 (Box 9, Folder 154)
    - "U" general: drafts, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 155)
    - "V" general: drafts, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 156)
    - "W" general:drafts, 1942, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 157-60)
    - "Wind in My Hair"
      - Typescript, [1951 May 1] (Box 10, Folder 161)
      - Typescript, carbon, 1951 May 1 (Box 10, Folder 162)
    - Woman of This Earth
      - Contract, 1933 Dec 18 (Box 10, Folder 163)
      - Reviews, 1934 (Box 10, Folder 164)
    - "Y" general: drafts, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 165)
    - Unidentified: typescript and carbon, 1959 (Box 10, Folder 166)
    - Unidentified: draft fragments, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 167)
    - Clippings: printed poems, 1933-59 (Box 10, Folder 168)
      See also: Box 13, folders 255-257
  - SHORTER WORKS
    - "All Souls Eve"
      See: Oversize, Box 16, folder 281
    - "Aunt Sophronia's Ghost": typescript, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 169)
    - "Autobiographical Sketch of Frances Frost": typescript, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 170)
    - "Beloved Fool": typescript, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 171)
    - "Biography of My Son": typescript, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 172)
    - "The Departure": printed version from The Commonweal, 1935 Mar 29 (Box 10, Folder 173)
    - "Dog's Day": typescript, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 174)
    - "The Eternal Apprentice"
      See also: Oversize, Box 16, folder 282
      - Typescript (4 p.), [1935?] (Box 10, Folder 175)
      - Typescript (2 p.), n.d. (Box 10, Folder 176)
    - "Grandma and the Death Hound": printed version from The Commonweal, 1936 Jun 5 (Box 10, Folder 177)
    - "The Grateful Devil"
      See: Box 1, folder 13
    - "The Head of a Pin": typescript, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 178)
    - "The Heart Being Perished"
      - Broadcast script, 1962 Nov 9 (Box 10, Folder 179)
      - Sound recording on magnetic tape, 1963 May 6 (Box 10, Folder 180)
    - "His First Poem"
      See: "The Heart Being Perished", Box 10, folder 179
    - "The Home-For-Christmas Cat": typescript, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 181)
    - "How Glooscap Made the Birds"
    - "Hurdy-Gurdy"
      See: Oversize, Box 16, folder 283
    - "I Plant a Garden": typescript, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 182)
    - "Johnny Appleseed's Song": printed sheet music, 1950 (Box 10, Folder 183)
    - "The Little Aerial": typescript and carbon (Box 10, Folder 184)
    - "Little Kitty and the Handsome Man": typescript (Box 10, Folder 185)
    - "The Little Whistler"
      See: Oversize, Box 16, folder 284
    - "The Magic Brooms"
      - Early typescript, [1951?] (Box 10, Folder 186)
      - Typescript, [1951?] (Box 10, Folder 187)
      - Typescript, carbon, [1951?] (Box 10, Folder 188)
    - "Poetry: Cosmic Shorthand": typescript (Box 11, Folder 189)
    - "The Race of the Hospital Shirt": typescript, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 190)
    - "Rainy Sunday": typescript (Box 11, Folder 191)
    - "So Vast a Thing as Life": typescript, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 192)
    - "Song of the Leaves": printed sheet music, 1950 (Box 11, Folder 193)
    - "Squeakalong Wintergreen": typescript, 1952 Sep 29 (Box 11, Folder 194)
    - "The Squire's Bride"
    - "Taxi": typescript, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 195)
    - "Thief": typescript, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 196)
    - "This Was Love": printed in Story, vol. VII, no. 41, 1935 Dec (Box 11, Folder 197)
    - "Three Hundred and Sixty-Five Children"
    - "To America, with Love": typescript, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 198)
    - "The Trailer": typescript, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 199)
    - "We Like to Laugh at Night": typescripts, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 200)
    - "Wedding Present": typescript, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 201)
    - "The Wooden-Legged Rooster": typescript, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 202)
    - "Young Mom": typescript, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 203)
    - Unidentified story: typescripts, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 204)
    - Unidentified: draft fragments, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 205)
- Personal Papers, 1919-68; Series II; 1.25; (3 boxes)
  Boxes 12-14 hold Series II, Personal Papers, which are arranged alphabetically by type of material.
  - Awards, 1933-50 (Box 12, Folder 206)
  - Biographical information: clippings, 1930-59 (Box 12, Folder 207)
  - Birth certificate: certified copy, 1953 Mar 4 (Box 12, Folder 208)
  - Clippings collected by Frances Frost about poetry, 1937-59 (Box 12, Folder 209)
    See also: Box 13, folder 248
  - Correspondence
    - "A" general, 1948-56 (Box 12, Folder 210)
    - Abbe, George
      See: Box 12, folder 213
    - "B" general, 1937-57 (Box 12, Folder 211)
    - Barr, Stringfellow, 1933 Sep 25 (Box 12, Folder 212)
    - Book Club for Poetry, 1953-54 (Box 12, Folder 213)
    - Bynner, Witter, 1937 Nov 13 (Box 12, Folder 214)
    - "C" general, 1944-56 (Box 12, Folder 215)
    - DeRocco, Jovan, 1954 Sep 1 (Box 12, Folder 216)
    - "F" general, 1937-59 (Box 12, Folder 217)
    - "G" general, 1950-57 (Box 12, Folder 218)
    - "H" general, 1935-59 (Box 12, Folder 219)
    - Ideals Publishing Co., 1956-57 (Box 12, Folder 220)
    - Jackson, E. Shirley, 1937 Mar 11 (Box 12, Folder 221)
    - Kelm, Karlton, n.y. Feb 15 (Box 12, Folder 222)
    - "L" general, 1968, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 223)
    - Larson, Earl Roland, 1951 (Box 12, Folder 224)
    - "M" general, 1944-56 (Box 12, Folder 225)
    - "N" general, 1954-58 (Box 12, Folder 226)
    - "P" general, 1944-58 (Box 12, Folder 227)
    - "R" general, 1955 (Box 12, Folder 228)
    - Robinson, Edwin Arlington, 1933 (Box 12, Folder 229)
    - "S" general, 1944-55 (Box 12, Folder 230)
    - Stein, Gertrude (to Lindley Hubbell), 1938 (Box 12, Folder 231)
    - "T" general, 1948-59 (Box 12, Folder 232)
    - "V" general, 1954-57 (Box 12, Folder 233)
    - Whittlesey House Books for Young People, 1944-59 (Box 12, Folder 234)
    - Unidentified, 1933 Sep 15 (Box 12, Folder 235)
  - Drawings, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 236)
  - The Edward MacDowell Association, Inc.: annual report, 1936 (Box 12, Folder 237)
  - Financial records, 1937-58 (Box 12, Folder 238-42)
  - The Goldwin Smith Lectureship: handbill, 1931-32 (Box 12, Folder 243)
  - Journals: "Memorandum Book", 1919 (Box 12, Folder 244)
  - Journals: "Diary", 1919 Dec (Box 12, Folder 245)
  - Journals: "Germany", 1936 (Box 12, Folder 246)
  - Journals: "Record", 1939 (Box 13, Folder 247)
  - Journals: "Notebook", 1945-46 (Box 13, Folder 248)
  - Journals: "Woodstock", 1949 Sep 5 (Box 13, Folder 249)
  - Journals: loose notes, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 250)
  - Marriage certificate and papers, 1933 (Box 13, Folder 251)
  - Naturalization information, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 252)
  - Passport, 1936 (Box 13, Folder 253)
  - Photographs, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 254)
  - Scrapbook, 1930-32 (Box 13, Folder 255)
  - Scrapbook, 1939 Jan (Box 13, Folder 256)
  - Scrapbook, 1953-58 (Box 13, Folder 257)
  - Scrapbook of poetry by others, 1954 (Box 13, Folder 258)
  - Scrapbook of poetry by others, 1957 (Box 14, Folder 259)
  - Scrapbook of poetry by others, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 260-64)
  - Writing of Others
    - Bartlett, Alice Hunt, "Dynamics of American Poetry: CXIV": printed in The Poetry Review, vol. XXXVII, no. 5/6, 1946 (Box 14, Folder 265)
    - P., A. E., "Ad Germaniam Puella Arboris It", 1936 Jul 20 (Box 14, Folder 266)
    - Shuckburg, Richard, "Yankee Doodle", n.d. (Box 14, Folder 267)
- Oversize, 1948-76; 2; (2 boxes)
  Boxes 15-16 hold Oversize material from Series I. The papers are arranged in the same order as material in that series.
  - WRITINGS
    - Children's Books
      - The Cat That Went to College: research material, 1949-51 (Box 15, Folder 268)
      - Christmas Is Shaped Like Stars: page proofs, 1948 (Box 15, Folder 269)
      - Maple Sugar for Windy Foot
        - Galleys, [1949] Oct (Box 15, Folder 270)
        - Galleys, annotated, 1949 Oct (Box 15, Folder 271)
        - Page proofs, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 272)
        - Page proofs, corrected, 1949 Nov (Box 15, Folder 273)
      - Sleigh Bells for Windy Foot: galleys, corrected (Box 16, Folder 274)
      - Then Came Timothy
        - Galleys and graphic proofs, 1950 Apr (Box 16, Folder 275)
        - Page proofs, 1950 May (Box 16, Folder 276)
      - Windy Foot at the Country Fair: page proofs (Box 16, Folder 277)
    - Poetry
      - Christmas in the Woods
        - Galleys, corrected, 1976 Feb (Box 16, Folder 278)
        - Mock-ups, 1976 Mar (Box 16, Folder 279)
      - This Rowdy Heart: galleys, [1954] (Box 16, Folder 280)
    - Shorter Works
      - "All Souls Eve": manuscript sheet music, copy, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 281)
      - "The Eternal Apprentice": galleys, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 282)
      - "Hurdy-Gurdy": manuscript sheet music, copy, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 283)
      - "The Little Whistler": holograph sheet music, 1950 Jun 10 (Box 16, Folder 284)